PETER SARGALSKI



786.301.2121



MailForPJS@gmail.com



Hollywood, FL



tinyurl.com/PetesLinkedIn

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

As a seasoned product designer, I transform ambitious startup visions into beautiful, real-world solutions. I work closely with entrepreneurs, product teams and development teams to build the right software - efficiently, cost-effectively, and with a keen eye for design.

My code development experience, combined with first-hand startup experience, allows me to guide companies from initial concept through successful execution and scaling. Integrating individuals, workflows, and solutions.

17 years in tech, 21 designing, 11 leading teams

CORE EXPERTISE

- Design Strategy & Leadership
- Startup Advising & Consulting
- Design Systems & Architecture
- Launching New / Reimagining Existing Products
- Mobile / Desktop / SaaS Design
- App / Software Platforms / Data Visualization

SKILLS

- Mobile Apps, Software, SaaS
- · Adobe CC, Figma
- HTML, CSS, Email Templating, Javascript
- Video editing
- Ai Prompting

EDUCATION

2007 BFA in Design Florida Atlantic University

WORK HISTORY

Boston Cognitive - Product Designer October 2024 - Current

- Designed BoCA app from the ground up. This includes the app product itself, the website and app store materials.
- Redesigning the Boston Cognitive family of websites: Bostoncognitive.com , BoCA.bostoncognitive.com , Alz.life.
- Managed a small (4) remote team of a designers and developers.

Overproof - Director of Design March 2019 - October 2024

- Led UX strategy for 4 products (2 web, 2 mobile) serving 5 user types, contributing to \$1.5M revenue in 2024
- Managed and mentored team of 5 designers and coordinated with 2 external agencies to ensure design quality and project standards
- Created 3 comprehensive design systems and architectures improving consistency within the design team and development efficiency
- Led user research initiatives to optimize product features and user experience
- Defined project scopes and feature priorities in collaboration with crossfunctional teams

Boats Group - Lead UX/UI Designer August 2017 - March 2019

- Led design team of 5 designer/developers with full design control over 4 main Boats Group properties serving global watercraft e-commerce market
- Managed end-to-end design process from wireframes to production release, including prototyping, A/B testing, and design system development
- Founded company Designers Guild fostering cross-team design collaboration and culture development

Open English - Designer / Front End Developer August 2015 - March 2017

- Executed front-end development for 6 active properties
- Translated approved UI designs into responsive, cross-browser compatible code using Bootstrap, HTML5, and CSS3 best practices
- Led my second company-wide migration to a different CMS system (this time WordPress), ensuring seamless transition across all properties
- Conducted A/B testing and conversion rate optimization to improve user engagement and business metrics
- Managed email marketing campaigns and research emerging technologies to maintain competitive advantage

KLX Aerospace - UX Designer October 2014 - September 2015, Contractor until 2018

- Led UX strategy for world's largest aerospace parts supplier, optimizing B2B e-commerce experience serving global aviation industry. (NASDAQ: KLXI, 2018 was sold to Boeing)
- Drove usability improvements while maintaining brand integrity, guiding cross-departmental teams on visual strategy
- Delivered development-ready designs in collaboration with IT teams, contributing to front-end implementation
- Developed content strategy aligned with business goals for multiple web properties